OnMouseDown and its related functions
OnMouseDown 関数と、これに類似する関数により
can detect a click on a collider
コライダ または GUI テキスト要素をクリックしたことを
or a GUI text element.
検知することが出来ます。
In this example we have a door object
この例ではドアのオブジェクトがあり
that has a box collider and a rigidbody attached.
ボックス コライダがあり、 Rigidbody がアタッチされてます。
The script that I've written
あらかじめ準備されたスクリプトでは The script that I've written
has an OnMouseDown function
OnMouseDown 関数が含まれていて
and when that object is clicked
オブジェクトがクリックされたとき
we will Debug Log, meaning that we'll print to the console,
Debug.Log 、すなわちコンソール出力を実行して
''Clicked On The Door''.
''Clicked On The Door'' と表示します。
So when I press play.
このためゲーム再生を行えば
check my console and click on the door in the game
コンソールをチェックしつつ、ゲームのドアをクリックすれば
I get a Debug Log.
Debug.Log が使用されます。
Similarly we can make it do something more
同様にして、もっと面白いことをやってみましょう。 Similarly we can make it do something more
exciting. For example, adding a force
例えば、ドア オブジェクトがクリックされたときに
to the door object when it is clicked.
力（Force）が加わるようにしてみましょう。
So in this example I am adding a force
この例の中では、 オブジェクトの Forward 方向と逆向きに
in the inverse direction of its forward.
力（Force）を加えてみます。
So the door will be fired away
このため、ドアは Z 軸に沿って
from it's Z axis.
吹き飛ばされます。
And I am also switching on gravity
さらに重力をオンに切り替えて
so that it will fall down when it's clicked.
クリックされたときに倒れるようにします。
It looks like this.
結果は次のとおりになります。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)